It's been a while since they started announcing results.
なんば　むった
《結果発表が始まってから➡
しばらく経った｡➡
１人ずつ順番に
電話してくるとはいえ➡
I understand that they're calling each candidate individually,
ずいぶん待たせるじゃねぇか
ジャクサ
ＪＡＸＡ…》
but JAXA's really making me wait a long time.
《そろそろ くるんじゃねぇか
｢プルルルル｣って…》
Shouldn't be much longer.
The phone will start ringing.
Here it comes...
さあ 来るぞ～｡そろそろだ～｡
Any second now...
感じるぞ～｡
I can feel it...
This is it!
Mu,
here's some
Jell-O for
a 3
o'clock
snack.
Mu,
here's some
Jell-O for
a 3
o'clock
snack.
Mu,
here's some
Jell-O for
a 3
o'clock
snack.
Mu,
here's some
Jell-O for
a 3
o'clock
snack.
Mu,
here's some
Jell-O for
a 3
o'clock
snack.
Mu,
here's some
Jell-O for
a 3
o'clock
snack.
Mu,
here's some
Jell-O for
a 3
o'clock
snack.
Mu,
here's some
Jell-O for
a 3
o'clock
snack.
Mu,
here's some
Jell-O for
a 3
o'clock
snack.
Mu,
here's some
Jell-O for
a 3
o'clock
snack.
Mu,
here's some
Jell-O for
a 3
o'clock
snack.
Mu,
here's some
Jell-O for
a 3
o'clock
snack.
Mu,
here's some
Jell-O for
a 3
o'clock
snack.
Mu,
here's some
Jell-O for
a 3
o'clock
snack.
Mu,
here's some
Jell-O for
a 3
o'clock
snack.
Mu,
here's some
Jell-O for
a 3
o'clock
snack.
Mu,
here's some
Jell-O for
a 3
o'clock
snack.
Mu,
here's some
Jell-O for
a 3
o'clock
snack.
Mu,
here's some
Jell-O for
a 3
o'clock
snack.
Mu,
here's some
Jell-O for
a 3
o'clock
snack.
Mu,
here's some
Jell-O for
a 3
o'clock
snack.
Mu,
here's some
Jell-O for
a 3
o'clock
snack.
Mu,
here's some
Jell-O for
a 3
o'clock
snack.
Mu,
here's some
Jell-O for
a 3
o'clock
snack.
Mu,
here's some
Jell-O for
a 3
o'clock
snack.
Mu,
here's some
Jell-O for
a 3
o'clock
snack.
Mu,
here's some
Jell-O for
a 3
o'clock
snack.
Mu,
here's some
Jell-O for
a 3
o'clock
snack.
Mu,
here's some
Jell-O for
a 3
o'clock
snack.
Don't tell me they still haven't decided...
《まさか まだ決まってなくて…》
Secret JAXA Meeting
なすだ
(茄子田)ん～もう電話する時間
過ぎちゃってるけどねぇ➡
Secret JAXA Meeting
We were supposed to have called them by now,
ま～だ決まんないねぇ｡
もう どうしようかねぇ…｡
Secret JAXA Meeting
but we still haven't decided.
What should we do?
I suppose we could use Ghost Leg.
つるみ
(鶴見)こうなりゃ
アミダで決めますか｡
Might be faster just to shuffle and draw.
(原田)くじ引きが
早いんじゃないですか？
True...
じゃあねぇ アミダか くじ引きか
どっちで決めるかを➡
Then let's use Ghost Leg to decide which method we use.
アミダで決めようかねぇ｡
ghost
draw
Which way to go?
いや さすがに それはねぇか…｡
No, they aren't that silly...
あ～早く電話してくれ～｡
Why won't they call me, already?
プレッシャーに
押し潰されそうだ～｡
The pressure's killing me...
《ケンジには
もう連絡いったかな…？》
Has Kenji gotten his phone call?
How did he do?
《どうだったんだろう ケンジ…
それから せりかさん…》
And what about Serika?
Seven Days
Space Brothers
Before my uneasiness
was the end
of my happiness
I came to you
and we were one
Hello Hello
Let's fly
Here in this world we dream
and keep on dancing
Here among light and shadow
we keep changing
so that the wind doesn't let up
Even though the future is vague and unreliable
we are
not alone
#36 Dancing Astronaut
Congratulations.
おめでとう｡それでは…｡
Goodbye, then.
Makabe Kenji
Tokyo
Education
まかべ
(鶴見)第一号は真壁君…と｡
The first call was to Makabe.
(鶴見)さて お次は…➡
Okay, moving on.
Ghost Leg, Ghost Leg...
Can't wait to see what it brings...
Itou
Machiko...
ま～ちこちゃん せりちゃ～ん➡
Seri,
we're here.
来たでぇ～ 神戸の
おじいと おばあが来たでぇ～｡
Your grandma and grandpa are here from Kobe.
(おじい)天気エエけど 神戸より
ちょっと寒いな 横浜は｡
The weather's nice.
But compared to Kobe, Yokohama is a little chilly.
かあ
とう
(まちこ)お義母さん お義父さん➡
Mother and Father, welcome.
いらっしゃい
遠いところ どうも どうも｡
Thank you for making the long trip.
とお
そんな遠ないで
あっちゅう間やったわ｡
It wasn't so long.
No time at all.
せりちゃん おらんのか？
Is Seri here?
Oh, Serika just went to visit Rinpei's grave.
(まちこ)あっ せりかは さっき
りんぺい
凛平さんのお墓に｡
ぶつだん
なんや うちに仏壇あんのに
わざわざ墓行ったんか｡
But you have an altar at home.
Oh...
あ 私 持ちます｡
Let me take that for you!
No, I'm fine.
おう 平気や｡ノープロブレンや｡
No problem.
(まちこ)昔 仏壇に置いてあった
せりかの日記を➡
One time, Serika left her diary by the altar.
私が読んじゃったもんだから
怒って怒って…｡
And when I read it, she was so mad.
それ以来 ずっと
お墓の方に行くのよ｡
Since then, she's gone to his grave instead.
Oh, really?
なんや そ～か｡
ナイーブちゃんやな｡
She's so naïve.
Wow, you brought so much.
わぁ すごいたくさん｡
そやろ｡
Yep.
せりちゃんに また い～っぱい
おも
食べてもらおう思て➡
We dropped by the Kobe Chinatown,
so we could pick up enough for Seri.
神戸の中華街で
ようさん買うてきたわ｡
へへっ こっちにも中華街が
あんのにな｡挑戦的やろ？
You have your own Chinatown here.
But we like to be different.
(おばあ)凛平…せりちゃん お墓
行っとうらしいわ｡➡
Rinpei,
it sounds like Seri went to visit your grave.
お墓で待っといたりぃ｡
You should go and wait for her.
ま 近いからな｡
あっちゅう間やわ｡
Well, it isn't far.
Shouldn't take long.
ほんで どないやったんや？
まちこちゃん｡せりちゃんの結果｡
So tell us, Machiko...
How did Seri do?
(おじい)そや 電話あったんやろ？
ジャクサンから｡
Right.
Didn't JAXA call?
Yes...
(せりか)日記 持って帰るね｡
続きは また来年｡
I'll take my diary home now.
Next year, you'll have more to read.
Dad...
お父さん…｡
ただいま～｡
I'm home.
おかえり｡どうだった？ダンス｡
Welcome home.
How was your dance lesson?
ん～ 発表会まで秘密｡
You don't get to know until the recital.
それよりさぁ～ パピコ２つ
あるんだけど どっちか食べる？
Anyway, I have two Papicos... Want one?
両方 食べる気だな｡
You'll eat both if I don't say I want one.
ふふふ もう両方かじっちゃった｡
I already opened both.
まあ いいや｡あげる｡
やった～！ふふふ｡
Okay, you can have them both.
Yay!
Anyway, come look at this, Serika.
それより
のぞ
こっち来て覗いてみな せりか｡
ボルボックスっていう藻の一種だ｡
This is Volvox, a type of algae.
ふご～い！キエイだね～｡
Wow!
It's pretty.
Isn't it?
なっ？小さな世界も
宇宙みたいだろ？
This tiny world is like its own little universe.
ホントだ 宇宙っぽい｡
踊っちゃうね こりゃ！
You're right.
It looks like one!
Makes me wanna dance!
Hey, don't dance now!
おいおい 今踊んなって｡
あっ パピコが飛ぶ…｡
You'll squirt Papico everywhere.
大丈夫だよ～ フンフン～｡
エヘヘ…｡
It's okay...
(凛平)父さんは 細胞とかを
検査する病理医だから➡
I'm a pathologist who focuses on individual cells,
こっちの小さい宇宙
専門だけどな➡
so I specialize in little universes.
行けるもんなら 大きい宇宙にも
行ってみたいんだよな…｡
Though if possible, I'd love to go to space and see the big one.
私も宇宙行く｡
I'm going to go to space.
そうか
宇宙飛行士になるんだな 将来｡
Are you, now?
You're going to become an astronaut?
そう！フフフッ｡
Yep.
踊る宇宙飛行士！フフ…｡
A dancing astronaut!
現在
冷たっ｡
Cold!
おっ あった！
Found one!
パピコ食～べよ 寒いけど～｡
I'll have a Papico.
It's too cold, though.
≪いらっしゃい≫
Welcome.
ただいま～｡
I'm home.
ちょっと大丈夫？あなた！
W-Wait, are you okay?
Dear?
Yeah...
ああ…アハハ｡➡
なんか急に
足の力が抜けちゃって…｡
My legs suddenly just gave out on me.
立てる？
Can you stand?
Y-Yeah...
(まちこ)せりか…ちょっと…｡
なに？
Serika...
Hmm?
Come here.
What is it?
お父さんね
入院することになったの｡
Your dad needs to be hospitalized.
Huh?
先生の話だと
お父さん 脳の病気で➡
According to the doctor,
your dad has a brain disorder that will slowly paralyze his body...
そのせいで だんだん 体が
動かなくなってくるんだって…｡
そんなの…やだ…｡
I don't want that to happen...
《やだ…‼》
I don't...
お見舞いは大丈夫だから
できるだけ行こう｡
We'll be allowed to visit him,
so we'll go as often as we can.
せりかは 学校の帰りとかに
行ってあげて｡
You can visit him on your way home from school.
お母さんは 仕事の合間
見つけて行くから｡
仕事？
I'll try to find time when I'm not working.
Working?
お母さんね
仕事始めることにしたの｡➡
I'm going to start working again.
I'll be returning to my old job.
前まで働いていたところに
またお世話になる｡
Dad...
お父さん…｡
退院って いつくらい？
When can you leave the hospital?
次のダンスの発表会 間に合う？
Will it be before my next dance recital?
どうかな…｡
I'm not sure...
１つ頼みがあるんだ｡
I have a request for you.
せりか
日記を書いてくれないか｡➡
Serika, could you start a journal?
父さん ちょっと
入院が長引きそうなんだ｡
It looks like I'll be in the hospital for a while.
退院するまでの間でいいからさ｡
It's just for while I'm stuck here.
せりかにとって 毎日が
どんな日だったのか➡
I want to know what's going on with you every day.
それだけ知りたいんだよ｡
わかった｡
じゃあ 退院するまで書くね｡
Okay,
I'll keep a diary while you're in the hospital.
よし！
Okay...
《今日が私にとって
どんな日だったか全部書くね》
I'm going to write down everything I can think of about today.
《日記だけど
お父さんへの手紙みたいに…》
It's a diary,
Dear Dad,
but I'll make it like a letter to Dad.
まず 今日の朝ごはんは
トーストに いちごジャム➡
First, for breakfast, I had toast with strawberry jam.
Bacon, eggs, and broccoli...
ベーコンエッグとブロッコリー…｡
36th
Dance Recital
よかったよ｡見たかったんだ｡
最後のとこ 上手になったな｡
That was wonderful.
I wanted to see you dance.
You've really improved on that last part.
わかった？
You could tell?
36th
Dance Recital
I'll leave you a DVD of the recital.
発表会のＤＶＤ 置いてくね｡
最後…今の方が
うまく踊れたんだけどね｡
But the last part wasn't as good...
I'll close my eyes and remember the dance I just saw.
最後んとこは 目ぇつぶって
今のを想い出すよ｡
(まちこ)そうよ 何年にも
なるかもしれない｡➡
That's right...
It may take years.
We have to make a decision.
いつか決めないといけないの｡➡
人工呼吸器を付けるかどうか…➡
Should we put him on a respirator?
We have to consider our options.
だって考えておかないと｡➡
そういう病気なんだから！
It is that serious!
(凛平)どうした？せりか｡
What's wrong, Serika?
お父さんの病気…➡
Are you gonna
治らないの？
get better?
お父さんも いろいろ
研究したんだけどな…➡
I've done a lot of research,
原因がわからない…
but we don't know what's causing this.
なんびょう
難病なんだ｡
It's a rare disease...
どうだ 日記書いてるか せりか？
So, have you been writing in your diary, Serika?
(カチ カチ…)
Mukai Chiaki
ハァ～…｡
Hey, Dad...
ねぇ お父さん｡
私が お父さんの病気 治す｡
I'm going to cure you.
え？じゃあ 医者になるのか？
Huh?
You're going to become a doctor?
宇宙飛行士に
なりたいんじゃなかったのか？
Didn't you want to be an astronaut?
向井千秋さんだって
お医者さんで宇宙飛行士だよ｡
Mukai Chiaki is both.
The International Space Station's Kibo module is a laboratory.
国際宇宙ステーションの｢きぼう｣
の中は 実験室になっててね➡
無重力を活かした医学実験が
できるんだって｡
You can perform medical experiments in zero gravity.
重力がなければ きれいな
タンパク質の結晶が作れるから➡
You can grow high-quality protein crystals in zero gravity,
脳の病気の原因も 地上より
ちゃんと研究できるんだよ｡
making brain disorders easier to identify.
だから 宇宙だと治療法も
見つかるかもしれない｡
That means you can discover new cures in space...
お父さんの病気も
治せるかもしれないよ｡
And I may be able to cure your illness!
驚いたな｡
I'm amazed...
今 勉強中なの！
I've been studying.
…そうか｡わかった｡
せりかに治してもらうよ｡
I see.
Okay, then I'll let you cure me.
楽しみだな｡
Yep.
I'm excited now...
せりかが医者の宇宙飛行士かぁ｡➡
You're going to become an astronaut doctor.
早くみてみたいなぁ｡
I can't wait to see that...
それまで生きないとな…｡
I'll have to hang on until then...
現在
《生きてて…ほしかった…》
I wish he could have...
《お父さんに…
見ててほしかった》
I wanted Dad
to see this...
《私が 宇宙に飛び出す瞬間を…
見ててほしかった》
I wanted
Dad to be watching
when I went into space!
《お父さん…私…➡
Dad...
I'm...
宇宙に行けるんだよ！》
on my way to outer space!
[ｹｲﾀｲ](鶴見)⦅伊東さん➡
Itou,
おめでとうございます｡合格です⦆
congratulations.
You passed!
おっと…ダメだ｡
Oops...
No more of that.
《泣くのはまだ早い｡➡
It's too early to cry...
私はまだスタートライン｡
泣くな！》
I've only reached the starting line.
Don't cry!
Okay...
よ～し｡
いただきます！
Time to eat.
ウフフ！
あん時の味だ！
It tastes exactly the same!
ハハハ…！フフフ…！
ハハハ…ハァ…｡
My right hand spent its days afraid of losing something
but wished to be held by my left hand
I lead you by the hand
Is my hand only there to hold my own hand now?
I can't lose it
Amidst my nagging disappointment that I can do nothing
I felt I wanted to do something
I let go again
I'm not alone in this world
If my hands can only hold two things
then I hope one of them is you
Not alone, not alone
I want our hearts to be connected
I want to be connected
＜あの… ＪＡＸＡの皆さん➡
Next time, on
Space Brothers
#37 Two Men in the Park
Uh, JAXA?
私の合格発表を
忘れてらっしゃいませんか？＞
Have you forgotten about me?
ほしか
＜全部１人で電話する気か？
ツルミー＞
Are you planning to call everyone yourself, Tsurumi?
Then you'll also have to tell people they failed.
＜じゃあ 不合格を伝えるつらさも
味わってもらうぞ＞
＜私の身には
小さなラｯキーが重なりまくる＞
I've been catching all these little lucky breaks.
＜逆に 不吉！限られている運が
どんどん減って➡
Is this an unlucky sign?
What little I had is being drained.
I'm probably running on empty!
もう 多分 すっからかんだ＞
Next time, on Space Brothers:
"Two Men in the Park"
＜俺は こういうのは
空の下で伝えたい＞
I believe that this should be said under the sky.
(南波日々人)パンパカパーン！
This Week's Space Photo
The medaka fish are also returning!
This week's space photo!
今週の宇宙写真で～す！
すっげぇ！
Awesome!